AYOMIDE AYANWOLA ISRAEL

I am a passion-driven full-stack engineer that loves learning and building innovative solutions. I have over 5+ years of experience as a software engineer. In my leisure time, I write technical articles and volunteer as a backend tutor at GDSC.

EXPERIENCE

Spacepen Technologies, Software Agency — DevOps Engineer

OCTOBER 2021 - PRESENT

- Deployed 3 website projects built by teammates.
- Supporting team members by teaching them to use GitHub for collaboration.
- Managed MySQL database, and performance tuning. Increased database performance to be used by multiple APIs.

Xcrowme, Fintech — Team Lead

SEPT 2020 - PRESENT

- Led a team of 3 developers.
- Designed application architecture and implemented using Django rest framework. Used Django security policies as the app interact with multiple payment gateways.
- Deployed workflows that run tests and deployed apps directly from Github for CI/CD. Reduced time to production by 15%.
- Set up a Webhook service that uses Redis key-value store to track and monitor event deliveries.

Fiverr - Freelance Developer

NOV 2019 - PRESENT

- Deployed multiple Django applications on Cloud technologies.
- Ensured 100% testing code coverage.
- Designed applications using PostgreSQL databases for Full-text search and Spatial GIS location analysis.
- Built several client-side applications using React and NextJs.

PROJECTS

Bookay - NextJS, Typescript, ReactJS

https://github.com/devvspaces/bookay

- Deployed an online bookstore on Vercel.
- Wrote a Form component builder to quickly generate forms and validate inputs.
- Communicated with the backend and file database using APIs

• Wrote tests for components and services.

DeepLegal - Django, PostgreSQL, GPT3, AWS

http://deeplegal.org/

- Designed a lazy application architecture that scrapes information on the go.
- Enabled full-text query searches using PostgreSQL.
- Optimized full-text queries by using Gin Indexes in PostgreSQL.
- Added OpenAI GPT3 for smart answers to user questions.
- Deployed web application and database using EC2 instances.

EDUCATION

University of London, Goldsmith College - BSc Computer Science

Course modules include Software design and development, Agile Software projects, and Databases. Managed time effectively to regularly meet deadlines while working full-time.

Federal University of Technology, Akure - BSc Computer Science

Course modules include Python programming, Operating Systems, Data structures, and Algorithms. Collaborated with other students to work on projects while studying.

AWARDS

Hacktoberfest Open Source - https://www.holopin.io/@netrobe